NISHAN KHADKA

Professional Profile

I have graduated as a software developer with a master's degree in system analysis from Charles Sturt University, Brisbane. Before joining my Masters I worked as a UX/UI developer in a software there I used numerous different tools such as figma and adobe products. I worked as a UXUI developer for about a year after the completion of my bachelor's degree. I come from a printing press background and have always been fascinated by graphic design, among other programs. I am passionate about designing and can work within a team or individually.

Key Knowledge

- HTML5
- CSS
- GIT
- FIGMA
- SEO
- WORDPRESS
- USER EXPERIENCE (UX)
- GRAPHIC DESIGN

Education

Masters in information System

July 2019 - Sept 2021

Charles Sturt University, Brisbane, Australia

Key Subjects: - System Analysis, Project Management, Information Security, IT Management Issues, Database Systems Data Mining and Visualization,

Achievements – Topics in ITS Ethics, Database System, Programming Principle

Bachelors in Information technology

Aug 2015 - Sept 2018

University of Northampton, Northampton, Australia

Key Subjects: -

Achievements – Web Development, Software Development, Database

Academic Projects

Increasing the protection of chat networks against institutionalized mass And targeted surveillance

Sep 2019 – Sep 2021

Charles Sturt University, Brisbane

In the final semester I did a dissertation on **increasing the protection of chat networks against institutionalized mass and targeted surveillance.** Nowadays, messaging apps are the most common and widely used mode of communication. Ever more popular the technology becomes, the more susceptible it becomes to attackers who wish to exploit the data because of their own gain. While customers may be unaware, there is indeed a possibility that they've been watched by a firm or the authorities. Data & mass spying has become a big threat for social networking programmes over time. During the course of this endeavor, more than 30 relevant publications, authentic sites, journals, & blogs are utilized To provide much more secure apps, the majority of the programmes have been upgraded using end-to-end encryption protocols & HTTPS encryption utilizing SSL certificates. Several third-party programs, like VPN, provide great protection against selective and bulk surveillance. Furthermore, cryptography encryption demonstrates a safe platform for data exchange by converting plaintext data into coded form. This article will analyze various security models and recommend the optimal security framework for both the chat program's fight against massive and targeted monitoring, as well as analyze and contrast various chatting portals & their security procedures.

Torrens Hotel Reservation System

Sep 2019 – Sep 2021

Torrens University, Brisbane

In the final semester, we group of 3 designed any sort of software and describe the process involved in designing the software. We followed all the software development life cycle process and designed the website. From Interviewing with the stakeholders, comparing the similar system, designing the wireframes, developing a detailed user

requirements documents to writing clean and commented code and revising it again and again we did our best and made one of the best website comparing to our competitors.

Objective: The main goal of the project was to create a clean and simple website and understand the software

development process that happens during the development.

Tools: PHP, HTML5, CSS and Bootstrap were used during the development of website. For the wireframes

lucid chart was used. For the testing Black box testing was used.

Duties: It was a group project and I was leading the project as I had experience in the website development.

Here I worked with all the group members and separated tasks to them seeing their capabilities. I assigned them the preliminary task like interviewing with the stake holders, getting feedback from the stokeholds by creating yes no questions. My role was to create a clean and simple website after getting all the requirement from the stakeholders. And then I handed over my work to my peers for reviews and testing where they tested from not only software developer side but also from the

customer side. Then final revision was done by me before submitting the project.

Outcome: The main objective of the project was to create a clean and simple Hotel reservation system and we

reached our goal within the given time frame. Customers were easily able to make a reservation from any were around the globe. The system was reliable, smoother, versatile, and flexible and the speed of the website loading time was also good. So overall we reached our goal. Moreover if we had much more time then we would add some of the better functionality where people who had difficulty in seeing would also be able to use the system properly. Not only had this had much we would also chat system to our website where customer can talk about the issues and get their issues fixed instantly. There's always place for improvement so there were lots of functionalities to be added if we had enough time period. And yes we had done presentation and taken all the feedback and kept it for future improvements. We had also written detailed project document where each and every chunk invoked during the project development

were described in detail.

Employment History

Junior Software Developer Urban Software Institute, Sunshine Coast, Australia Duties

Jan 2022-April 2022

- Support with the documentation of the organization's business processes
- Actively undertake and participate in software quality assurance
- Use DevOps to manage tasks daily to ensure all assigned tasks are completed and delivered according to organizational priorities Handle external data securely and confidentially
- Identify new improvements in procedures and technologies that can add value and improve efficiencies in the delivery of systems and interfaces
- Test and deploy programs and systems
- Willingness to assist and support others as required to meet deadlines
- Responsible for estimating, planning and managing all our own tasks and reporting on progress
- Mentor and supervise interns when required
- Participate in the development of a healthy and safe workplace, embracing initiatives, information and training.

- Demonstrate safe work behaviors, abiding by procedures, identifying and reporting hazards, and contributing to all aspects of a safe workplace culture
- Such other relevant duties as required from time to time which would generally fall within the scope of this position.

UX/UI Designer April 2015–June 2018 Lighgtweb Group Pvt Ltd, Kathmandu, Nepal

Duties

- Met with the client and did all the software engineering requirements following the agile methodology
- Interview with the stakeholders to point out the changes they wish to see in the new system
- Provided PHP, CSS, Bootstrap, Word Press training to the juniors
- Conducted testing and review of website design for responsiveness, clarity and effectiveness.
- Worked in Agile-driven environment to effectively maintain project timelines and utilize available resources.
- Revised, modularized and updated old code bases to modern development standards, reducing operating costs and improving functionality. Responsible for estimating, planning and managing all our own tasks and reporting on progress
- Mentor and supervise interns when required
- Participate in the development of a healthy and safe workplace, embracing initiatives, information and training.
- Demonstrate safe work behaviors, abiding by procedures, identifying and reporting hazards, and contributing to all aspects of a safe workplace culture
- Such other relevant duties as required from time to time which would generally fall within the scope of this position.

Personal Attributes

One at a time

I always followed the agile methodology from the beginning of my software development journey. Here we are assigned one task at a time and after the completion of that task we will be able to move to the other task. This has set a good habit for building my personality. Instead of putting hands in every task and brining a small output I believe in focusing on a small chunk and brining the quality.

Eye to Details

As I have mentioned before I worked with my father in his printing press at the age of 16. There of the main plate becomes wrong then whole print would be mistake so there we need to do the proofreading in a next level. Hence I have an eye to details.

Communication Skills

While working in the software company for the last 3 years we need to communicate with each and every stake

holders and provide them the result or explain the progress of the project in a polite manner. Hence I developed communication skills from there.

Quality over Quantity

Quality always wins over quantity in every field. Instead of doing 5 tasks in a day and not completing a single job properly I would do 1 task in a day and make it finest.

References

Available upon request